<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inclusion on NeuroDiv</title>
    <link>https://neurodiv.blog/en/tags/inclusion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inclusion on NeuroDiv</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 17:00:30 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://neurodiv.blog/en/tags/inclusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neurodiversity and Inclusion at Work: Towards a Silent Revolution</title>
      <link>https://neurodiv.blog/en/articles/2025/002-neurodiversite-et-inclusion-au-travail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 17:00:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurodiv.blog/en/articles/2025/002-neurodiversite-et-inclusion-au-travail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neurodiversity refers to the natural variation in human neurological functioning. It includes profiles such as autism, ADHD, dyslexia, dyspraxia, Tourette’s syndrome, among others. In the professional world, these differences are often perceived as obstacles… when in fact they can be true assets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenges-faced-by-neurodivergent-individuals&#34;&gt;The Challenges Faced by Neurodivergent Individuals&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lack of understanding: Employers and colleagues may be unaware of the specific needs related to neurodiversity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Inadequate sensory environments: Noisy open-plan offices, harsh lighting, frequent interruptions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Standardized recruitment processes: Traditional interviews can disadvantage brilliant but atypical candidates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stigmatization and isolation: Behavioral or communication differences may be misinterpreted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-lack-of-understanding&#34;&gt;1. Lack of Understanding&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In many professional settings, neurodiversity remains a little-known concept. Employers and colleagues may ignore the cognitive or sensory particularities of their neurodivergent teammates, leading to misunderstandings, snap judgments, or unrealistic expectations. For example, an autistic person who avoids eye contact or prefers to work alone may be seen as distant or uncollaborative, when they are simply protecting their equilibrium. This lack of understanding can damage working relationships and hinder the growth of atypical talents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Neurodiversity?</title>
      <link>https://neurodiv.blog/en/articles/2025/001-qu-est-ce-que-la-neurodiversit%C3%A9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 17:00:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neurodiv.blog/en/articles/2025/001-qu-est-ce-que-la-neurodiversit%C3%A9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Definition of neurodiversity: What is neurodiversity? Distinction between neurotypical and neurodivergent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History of the concept: Origin of the term, evolution of the perception of neurological differences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why this blog? Importance of raising awareness, debunking misconceptions, and promoting inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-neurodiversity&#34;&gt;What Is Neurodiversity?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neurodiversity is a concept that highlights the diversity of human brains and minds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not about emphasizing a deficit, but rather about recognizing that we are all different in how our brains function: each person&amp;rsquo;s neurological system is unique.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
